Finding Aid for Housing Division (University of Michigan) publications, 1923-2003
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Sub-Unit Publications
  - Housing Research Office
    - Reports
      - A Tide on Which All Boats Rise: The Effects of Living-Learning Program Participation on Undergraduate Outcomes at the University of Michigan, 1989 (Box 7)
  - Housing Special Programs
    - Anthologies
      - Ethnic Reflections, 1979-1988 (Box 7)
    - Brochures 1979, 1987, undated (Box 7)
    - Catalogs
      - Minority Films Catalog, undated (Box 7)
    - Manuals
      - Funding Referral Guide, 1983 (Box 7)
      - Minority Peer Advisor Training Manual, circa 1980 (Box 7)
      - Operation Plan, 1993 (Box 7)
    - William Monroe Trotter House
      - Brochures 1989 (Box 7)
  - Mediation Services
    - Bulletins 1986-1990, undated (Box 7)
    - Reports circa 1960 (Box 7)
  - Off-Campus Housing Program
    - Brochures
      - Fraternities at the University of Michigan, 1979/80, undated (Box 7)
      - Sororities at the University of Michigan, undated (Box 7)
    - Bulletins
      - Off-Campus Housing, 1964-1995, undated, 4 folders
      - Safety and Sanitation Manual for Small Group Houses, 1977 (Box 7)
    - Newsletters
      - Off Campus Housing Newsletter, 1968-1970 vol. 1-3 (Box 7)
  - Office of Student Relations
    - Manuals
      - Residence Hall Judicial Process: A Handbook for Students, 1993/94 (Box 8)
  - Physical Properties Department
    - Reports
      - Physical Properties Report, 1980-1981 (Box 8)
  - Pilot Program/College Community Program
    - Annual Reports 1986-1987 (Box 8)
    - Brochures 1970-1995, undated (Box 8)
    - Bulletins 1977-1980 (Box 8)
    - Calendars 1975-1976 (Box 8)
    - Programs 1975 (Box 8)
  - President's Commission on Off-Campus Housing
    - Reports
      - Student Housing: Report of the President's Off-Campus Housing Commission, 1965 (Box 8)
  - Residence Hall Rate Committee
    - Reports
      - Residence Hall Rate Committee Report, 1971/72 (Box 8)
  - Residence Halls
    - Alice Lloyd
      - Anthologies
        - Ego: Through the Looking Glass, undated (Box 8)
      - Brochures 1992-1994 (Box 8)
      - Manuals
        - Alice Lloyd Hall Dorm Booklet, 1982/83, undated (Box 8)
        - Alice Lloyd Hall Handbook and Constitution, 1963/64 (Box 8)
      - Newsletters 1973 (Box 8)
    - Alumnae House
      - Directories
        - Budget of News, 1942 (Box 8)
    - Barbour
      - Regulations 1936 (Box 8)
    - Barbour/Newberry
      - Brochures 1992-1994 (Box 8)
      - Manuals 1975, undated (Box 8)
    - Bursley
      - Brochures 1992-1994, undated (Box 8)
      - Manuals
        - Bursley Community Volunteers, 1988-1989 (Box 8)
        - Bursley Hall Handbook (Orientation Handbook), 1979-1982, undated (Box 8)
      - Newsletters
        - The Jon Door, 1973-1976 (Box 8)
        - University of Michigan Bursley Hall, 1979 (Box 8)
    - Cambridge House
      - Brochures 1992-1994 (Box 8)
    - Couzens
      - Brochures 1992-1994 (Box 8)
      - Manuals 1974, 1974-1984 (scattered) (Box 8)
      - Newsletters 1929 (Box 8)
    - East Quad
      - Brochures 1992-1994 (Box 8)
      - Guidebooks
        - Truckin' Around Town: A Guide to Survival in East Quad and Ann Arbor, undated (Box 8)
      - Manuals
        - East Quad and its Academic Units: A Guide, undated (Box 8)
        - East Quad Hymnal, 1970/71, undated (Box 8)
        - A Guide to Communal Living, 1969 (Box 8)
        - Survivor's Guide, 1981/82, undated (Box 8)
      - Newsletters
        - The East Wind, 1987/88 (Box 8)
        - Omphos, undated (Box 8)
        - The Resurrection, 1972 (Box 8)
      - Programs 1969 (Box 8)
    - Fletcher
      - Brochures 1992-1994, undated (Box 8)
      - Manuals
        - The Men of Fletcher Hall, 1983-1985 (Box 8)
    - Henderson House
      - Yearbooks
        - Henderson House, 1958-1967 (Box 8)
    - Inter-House Council
      - Newsletters 1957 (Box 8)
    - Markley
      - Anthologies 1981 (Box 8)
      - Brochures 1992-1994 (Box 8)
      - Cookbooks undated (Box 8)
      - Manuals 1963-1982, 3 folders (Box 8)
      - Newsletters
        - Markely Notes, 1972 (Box 8)
        - The Toilet Paper, 1969/70 (Box 8)
    - Mosher Jordan
      - Brochures 1930-1994 (Box 8)
      - Manuals
        - Mosher Hall Blue Book, undated (Box 8)
        - Mosher Michigan, 1965/66 (Box 8)
        - Mosher Jordan (Orientation Handbook), undated (Box 8)
        - Welcome to Mo Jo, 1978-1984 (Box 8)
    - Oxford Housing
      - Anthologies 1974 (Box 8)
      - Brochures 1992-1994, undated (Box 8)
      - Cookbooks undated (Box 8)
      - Manuals 1963-1982 (scattered), 2 folders (Box 8)
    - South Quad (Box 9)
      - Brochures 1992-1994 (Box 9)
      - Manuals
        - About South Quad: A Guide to Good Living in South Quad, 1987-1988 (Box 9)
        - South Quadrangle, 1964-1979, undated (scattered) (Box 9)
      - Newsletters 1979, 1981, undated (Box 9)
    - Stockwell
      - Brochures 1992-1994 (Box 9)
      - Manuals
        - 1964-1966 (Box 9)
        - 1978-1982 (Box 9)
      - Programs 1976 (Box 9)
    - Vera Baits
      - Brochures 1992-1994, undated (Box 9)
      - Manuals
        - Information, 1970-1982 (scattered), 2 folders (Box 9)
        - Staff Manual, 1970-1971 (Box 9)
      - Newsletters
        - Baits Bullsheet, undated (Box 9)
        - The Hubbard Herald, 1975 (Box 9)
        - Verbatim
          - 1980-1981 vol. 2-5 (Box 9)
          - 1992-1993 vol. 13 (Box 9)
    - West Quad
      - Brochures 1978, 1992 (Box 9)
      - Manuals 1970-1977, undated (Box 9)
      - Newsletters 1952 (Box 9)
    - West Quad, Barbour, and Newberry (WQBN)
      - Manuals 1979-1985 (Box 9)
    - West Quad/Cambridge House
      - Brochures 1993-1994, undated (Box 9)
  - Residence Halls Associations
    - Constitution and By-Laws 1990 (Box 9)
    - Manuals
      - Residence Halls Association Handbook, undated (Box 9)
      - Resident Staff Resource Guide, 1986-1987 (Box 9)
    - Miscellaneous 1992-1997 (Box 9)
    - Newsletters
      - RHA Today, 1986 (Box 9)
      - RHAP Sheet, 1983-1986 (Box 9)
      - Resident Voice, 1986/87 (Box 9)
  - Residence Halls Computing Program
    - Newsletters
      - ResComp News: Residence Halls Computing Newsletter, 1987 (Box 9)
    - Proposals
      - A Proposal to Apple Computer, Inc. for Partial Funding of the Residence Halls Computing Program (ResComp) at the University of Michigan, undated (Box 9)
  - Residence Halls Libraries
    - Annual Reports
      - Annual Report of Coordinating Committee for Libraries in Women's Residence Halls, 1960/61 (Box 9)
      - Annual Report of Women's Residence Halls Library Coordinating Committee, 1961-1963, 2 folders (Box 9)
      - Annual Report Residence Halls Libraries, by Library Selections Committee, 1966/67 (Box 9)
      - Annual Report Residence Halls Libraries, by Head Librarians' Committee, 1970/71, 1973/74, 2 folders (Box 9)
      - Annual Reports, 1969-1993, 12 folders (Box 9)
    - Brochures undated (Box 9)
    - Manuals
      - The Charles H. Benzinger Memorial Library, East Quadrangle Manual of Policies and Procedures, 1984/85 (Box 10)
      - Manual of Policies and Procedures for Residence Hall Libraries, 1974 (Box 10)
      - Manual of Policies for Residence Hall Libraries at the University of Michigan, 1966-1968, 2 folders (Box 10)
      - Operations Manual for the Microsoft File Circulation System, 1992 (Box 10)
      - Operations Manual for Head Librarians, 1976, 3 folders (Box 10)
    - Reports
      - Library Selection Committee, 1964 (Box 10)
  - Women's Residence Halls Library Coordinating Committee
    - Manuals
      - Librarian's Handbook, 1961 (Box 10)
  - Solid Waste Management Task Force
    - Reports
      - Integrated Solid Waste Management for UM Housing: Final Report and Recommendations, 1988 (Box 10)
  - Twenty First Century Program
    - Brochures undated (Box 10)
  - University Apartments
    - Bulletins
      - University Housing, 1968-1971 (Box 10)
    - Manuals including lease information
      - 1962 1966 (Box 10)
      - 1969 1971 (Box 10)
  - University Apartment Facilities Rate Committee
    - Reports
      - Rate Committee Report for University Apartment Facilities, 1969-1971, 2 folders (Box 10)
      - University Apartment Facilities Rate Committee Minority Report, 1970/71 (Box 10)
  - University Task Force on Faculty, Staff and Student Housing Issues
    - Reports
      - Interim Report, February 2, 1990 (Box 10)
      - Interim Report, February 19, 1990 (Box 10)
      - Final Report, July 27, 1990 (Box 10)
      - Appendices A-F, undated, 1990, 4 folders (Box 10)
  - Women in Science and Engineering Residence Program
    - Brochures undated (Box 10)
- Topical Publications
  The Topical Publications series includes printed materials published to document specific events or activities such as fund-raising or one-time conferences hosted by the Housing Division. The Topical Publications series (.1 linear feet) includes printed material relating to Men's and Women's housing. The researcher might also consult the Couzens Hall publications found under Sub-Unit Publications, Residence Halls for more information about this program.
  - Men's Housing
    - Brochures 1943-1952, undated (Box 10)
    - Bulletins
      - Bulletin of Information, 1950/51, 1954/55 (Box 10)
    - Manuals
      - Staff Duties, undated (Box 10)
  - Women's Housing
    - Brochures 1923-1952, undated (Box 10)